<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-17T23:53:58+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Projects</title><subtitle>PhD Candidate working on diffusion MRI</subtitle><author><name>Ting Gong</name><email>gongting@zju.edu.cn</email></author><entry><title type="html">MTE-NODDI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MTE-NODDI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MTE-NODDI" /><published>2020-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MTE-NODDI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MTE-NODDI/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;multi-te-noddi-for-disentangling-non-t2-weighted-signal-fractions-from-compartment-specific-t2-relaxation-times&quot;&gt;Multi-TE NODDI for disentangling non-T2-weighted signal fractions from compartment-specific T2 relaxation times&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doi-to-the-paper-link&quot;&gt;DOI to the paper: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.116906&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conventional-noddi-derived-compartment-fractions-are-t2-weighted-and-te-dependent&quot;&gt;Conventional NODDI-derived compartment fractions are T2-weighted and TE-dependent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/MTE-NODDI/Figure2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Demonstration of TE-dependence of NODDI-derived parameters in the set of chosen WM (A)(C) and GM (B) ROIs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As demonstrated above, &lt;em&gt;fin&lt;/em&gt; increases with TE in all WM ROIs but remains relatively constant in the GM ROI; &lt;em&gt;fiso&lt;/em&gt; increases with TE in all WM and GM ROIs; in contrast, &lt;em&gt;ODI&lt;/em&gt; shows minimal TE-dependence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mte-noddi-disentangles-non-t2-weighted-signal-fractions-from-t2-relaxation&quot;&gt;MTE-NODDI disentangles non-T2-weighted signal fractions from T2 relaxation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/MTE-NODDI/Figure3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Distribution of all estimates from simulation data.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simulation data demonstrates the accuracy and precision of MTE-NODDI, and the in vivo data demonstrates the TE-dependence of NODDI estimated parameters and the ability of MTE-NODDI to exploit such TE-dependence. Compared to NODDI estimates, the estimates from MTE-NODDI suggest that conventional T2-weighted signal fractions will give overestimated relative intra-neurite and CSF fractions, due to the estimated T2 of intra-neurite compartment being larger than that of extra-neurite compartment from the proposed technique, and T2 of free water being larger than T2 of intra-neurite compartment in studies respectively. Meanwhile, the T2-weighted intra-neurite and CSF fractions will increase with TE. By disentangling the non-T2-weighted compartment fraction with its specific relaxation, the MTE-NODDI technique could facilitate the interpretation and quantification of studies where alteration of T2 and fraction interacts and where acquisition protocols (e.g. TE) are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/MTE-NODDI/Figure4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;MTE-NODDI estimated parameter maps and histograms of WM voxels. The parameter estimates show high consistency between the two subjects.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robust-estimates-with-reduced-number-of-tes&quot;&gt;Robust estimates with reduced number of TE’s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/MTE-NODDI/Figure6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The dependence of parameter estimates from simulation data of pure WM voxel on the number and range of TEs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reducing the number of TEs while keeping the same TE range, the accuracy and precision of parameter estimation closely mirror those of the full data, including the slight biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/MTE-NODDI/Figure7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The dependence of parameter estimates from in vivo data on the number and range of TEs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;non-t2-weighted-fractions-may-improve-the-interpretability-of-neurodevelopmental-studies&quot;&gt;Non-T2-weighted fractions may improve the interpretability of neurodevelopmental studies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For future applications, the MTE-NODDI could be beneficial to the understanding and interpretability of neuroimaging studies, especially for those investigating age-related brain alterations, in which substantial alterations of T2-weighted intra-neurite fraction and T2 relaxation time have been reported throughout the lifespan. For example, the T2-weighted intra-neurite fractions have been shown to increase during brain development (Kansagra et al., 2016) and maturation (Geeraert et al., 2019; Mah et al., 2017), followed with a plateau at adulthood (Kodiweera et al., 2016) and to decrease during aging (Cox et al., 2016; Merluzzi et al., 2016). In contrast, the T2 values in WM have been shown to decrease quickly during early development and decrease slower during maturation (Ding et al., 2004; Lee et al., 2018), followed by increasing in most brain regions and declining in a few regions during aging (Kumar et al., 2012). However, the intrinsic microstructural changes behind the development process remain unclear due to the limitations of conventional single TE method. With the ability to disentangle the T2-weighted signal fraction from T2 weighting, the MTE-NODDI developed in this study can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ting Gong</name><email>gongting@zju.edu.cn</email></author><category term="NODDI" /><category term="T2 relaxation" /><category term="Brain development" /><category term="Brain maturation" /><category term="Aging" /><summary type="html">Multi-TE NODDI for disentangling non-T2-weighted signal fractions from compartment-specific T2 relaxation times</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">H-CNN for fast DKI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/H-CNN-DKI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="H-CNN for fast DKI" /><published>2019-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/H-CNN-DKI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/H-CNN-DKI/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;fast-and-robust-diffusion-kurtosis-parametric-mapping-using-a-three-dimensional-convolutional-neural-network&quot;&gt;Fast and robust diffusion kurtosis parametric mapping using a three-dimensional convolutional neural network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DOI to the paper: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2919241&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ting Gong</name><email>gongting@zju.edu.cn</email></author><category term="DKI" /><category term="CNN" /><category term="hierarchical structure" /><category term="deep learning" /><summary type="html">Fast and robust diffusion kurtosis parametric mapping using a three-dimensional convolutional neural network</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CNN for fast fODF</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/CNN-fODF/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CNN for fast fODF" /><published>2019-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/CNN-fODF</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/CNN-fODF/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;fast-learning-of-fiber-orientation-distribution-function-for-mr-tractography-using-convolutional-neural-network&quot;&gt;Fast learning of fiber orientation distribution function for MR tractography using convolutional neural network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DOI to the paper: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/mp.13555&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ting Gong</name><email>gongting@zju.edu.cn</email></author><category term="MSMT-CSD" /><category term="CNN" /><category term="fODF" /><category term="fiber tractography" /><category term="deep learning" /><summary type="html">Fast learning of fiber orientation distribution function for MR tractography using convolutional neural network</summary></entry></feed>